My daughter, Shuitao, left home
during the You hour
and still hasn't returned, sir.
She died the same way
as the other three.
Her neck was snapped,
and her tongue cut out.
Time of death was the early Xu hour,
the night before last.
That's barely two hours apart
from Sun Mao's murder.
Her clothes are soaking wet.
Drenched from the rain.
Clearly,
she wasn't killed here.
A pouch?
(Xin'an County Bureau,
Record of Lian, Record of Lady Gui)
Case files.
=The Tang Mist S1=
=Episode 23=
(Justice and Clarity)
Yes.
Sun Mao was corrupt.
His reputation
was completely fabricated.
He even had my brother
fraudulently claim
the rewards from Wang Zhong.
(Deed of House Pledge)
As for house deed
and the land deed, he made my brother
buy them all on the cheap.
But,
as for why there's a corpse
in this secret room,
we honestly have no idea.
She's right, sir.
If we knew a dead body was hidden here,
my sister and I
would've never dared to stay.
How was Sun Mao
connected to these dead women?
Why did he hide
the case files for Lady Gui and Lian?
And why did he pay
to cover up their murders?
Sun Mao was greedy,
but he never
showed any interest in women.
I don't know what his connections
to the women were.
Sun Mao was an imperial official.
He played the part of an honest man,
but committed foul deeds in the dark.
He amassed a massive fortune,
yet dressed in cheap rags.
He didn't dare show his wealth,
let alone spend it.
What was the point of having such wealth
if he was constantly living in fear?
The fourth victim,
Shuitao.
Sun Mao must have killed her.
Why else would she
be hidden in his house?
In a secret room, no less.
It's possible
that whoever killed Sun Mao
did it to avenge
those poor women.
Sun Mao embezzled Wang Zhong's rewards.
Could Bai Zhi have found out
and sought revenge?
And what about this pouch?
The four victims' pouches
are all accounted for.
Could this pouch
belong to the killer?
Black,
with pink flowers.
Does it belong to a man or a woman?
Sir.
This is
a gold and silver-painted rosewood desk.
What of it?
Sir,
Princess Anning gifted this
to Mingguang Temple.
But five years ago,
it was supposedly destroyed in a fire.
It seems that fire
wasn't an accident after all.
The Buddha's mercy is boundless,
but he isn't omnipotent.
For worldly illnesses,
one must also seek medical treatment.
Don't place all your hopes
solely on the Buddha's blessing.
Take this prescription.
Thank you, Abbot.
Abbot. Commissioner Di is here.
Commissioner Di.
Officer!
When did you get so stuck-up
that you don't even notice me?
Sir!
Come here.
Sir,
did you find any clues?
Come on, tell me.
You know me
better than anyone.
I'm not one to gossip.
The progress of this case
is strictly confidential.
Confidential?
You're wearing it out in the open!
You got
this pouch from Bai Zhi, right?
That belongs to Bai Zhi?
A black pouch with pink peonies.
She sewed it herself.
You won't find
another one like it in Xin'an.
Everyone has seen it.
Most women prefer bright colors,
but Bai Zhi
always preferred black.
She said black
doesn't show dirt.
And those pink peonies
symbolize unwavering devotion.
They're the flowers of love.
That's the very flower
Wang Zhong held in his arms
when he came to propose.
I see you don't mind wearing it,
and so openly too!
Amitabha.
Just as you've discovered, sir,
Sun Mao was nothing like
the kind man everyone praised.
He was actually
a ruthless, corrupt official.
Five years ago...
Sir.
The Abbot is in the backyard
taking inventory
of Princess Anning's gifts.
(Five Years Ago)
If you need him,
I can go get him.
No need.
I'll just wait here.
Help!
Somebody help!
- Fire!
Sir, there's a fire!
Somebody come quickly!
Sir!
Put it out!
What are you doing?
Hurry!
Hurry up!
Over there!
Let's go.
Hurry!
Go!
Abbot Yuanzhi has
already perished in the flames.
If you wish to join him in the afterlife,
I'd be happy to oblige.
Wait.
I claimed the fire couldn't melt the gold
just to save this statue.
I simply couldn't bear
letting a man
with so much blood on his hands
defile the Buddha's golden body.
He promised you the Abbot's position?
Yes.
You wear the robes of a monk,
and have studied
the teachings for years.
Yet for your own greed,
you abandoned loyalty and righteousness.
It was a grave mistake,
and a betrayal of the Buddha.
Amitabha.
I have sinned.
That very night,
Sun Mao poisoned
all the soldiers involved in the arson.
As a prefectural official,
he held absolute power
over this entire region.
I'm just a simple monk.
How could I possibly fight him?
If everyone stood by out of fear,
where would we find
fairness or justice
in this world?
Fairness?
Justice?
I kept telling myself
that all mortals
make mistakes.
But ever since then,
my guilt has only grown heavier.
To atone for my sins,
I studied medicine
and set up a Repentance Room
to constantly repent.
I hoped that by doing so,
I could lessen my sins
and find peace.
What time did Bai Zhi
leave Mingguang Temple last night?
During the early Xu hour.
Officer.
Do you have your eye on Bai Zhi too?
Me?
Why else would you care so much
about her and Wang Zhong?
He's an official.
This has to be about the murders.
Could Wang Zhong
have killed the Prefect?
No way.
Wang Zhong used
to be a general, after all.
He wouldn't do that.
Did you forget about that incident?
Oh, right!
I remember now.
That incident!
Yes, that one!
Exactly!
Looks can be deceiving.
For a guy like him,
nothing he does would surprise me.
What guy?
What exactly happened?
I meant to tell you last time,
but you left too quickly.
Didn't I tell you
how the Prefect bailed Bai Zhi out?
That happened
over a month ago.
Last night,
some coins were stolen
from the south workshop.
Someone saw a man
with a limp climb the wall and escape.
It was you, wasn't it?
Me?
I didn't do it!
Where were you during the You hour?
The You hour?
It was raining heavily.
I was
rescuing a woman
on the west side of town.
Help!
Who can vouch for you?
- Exactly! Prove it!
- Yes! Yeah!
Who would know that?
That woman can testify for me!
What woman?
I always said Wang Zhong
didn't look like a good guy.
Only now you're saying that?
You old hag!
Why you...
I bet no one can vouch for him.
See for yourselves.
These are the injuries
my husband got
from saving that woman last night.
Here's our proof!
What kind of proof is that?
I bet you stole the money!
Search the place!
Stop!
Stop it!
Don't touch our things!
Move aside!
The money
- Stop!
- must be hidden around here.
Poor Bai Zhi.
Even though He Xun took her in,
she's still a proper lady.
Now her reputation is ruined,
and people are gossiping about her.
Took her in?
Yeah.
Sir.
These are black bean skins.
Also, when I was at Bai Zhi's house,
I smelled a strong scent of vinegar.
According to medical texts,
soaking black beans in vinegar
and boiling them together
to form a paste
creates a hair dye.
But it fades when exposed to water.
If it accidentally gets on the skin,
it leaves a black stain.
I suspect the stain on Sun Mao's hand
came from this exact paste.
It was raining heavily
the night Sun Mao died.
He must have
gotten into a struggle with Bai Zhi.
He grabbed her hair,
and because his right hand
was tightly clenched,
it was protected from the rain,
allowing the black stain to remain.
But it's common
for women to dye their hair.
That doesn't prove it was Bai Zhi.
It's a bite mark.
The burn on Sun Mao's hand
was deliberate.
It was meant
to cover up
a bite mark he received earlier.
The teeth marks are shallow,
and closely spaced.
Judging from the bite,
the front teeth are rounded,
the central incisors
are moderately wide,
and the lower teeth are neat and even.
Overall, the teeth are small and thin.
It must be a woman.
The shape of the dental arch
should match the width of her face,
and the shape of the teeth
should align with her lip line.
Her face
must have a delicate, oval shape.
Open up.
It was Bai Zhi.
Did Bai Zhi
really kill Sun Mao?
How could a single woman
drag a corpse to the front courtyard,
let alone throw it
into the incense burner?
She must've had help.
Commissioner Di.
You recognize me?
Zhi mentioned you.
She said you have a distinguished air,
easy to recognize.
Commissioner Di.
Zhong,
go back inside and rest.
I'll attend to our guest.
Alright.
Sir,
I'll leave you to it.
what can I do for you?
I'll get straight to the point.
My investigation shows that
the night before last,
you were at Mingguang Temple
until the Hai hour.
The black stain on Sun Mao's palm
came from your hair dye.
The bite mark on his hand
was also left during that time.
You met Sun Mao
and got into a struggle with him.
Why did you lie?
I...
I did see him.
Prefect,
let me go!
Wang Zhong is nothing
but a washed-up general.
He can't even provide for you.
Why don't you come
with me instead? I'll treat you well.
Where do you think you're going?
Come back!
Trying to run?
Help!
Where to?
Let me go!
When I heard he died early this morning,
I was terrified.
That's why I lied.
What time was this?
Late Xu hour.
It was raining heavily when I ran out.
By the time I got home,
it was the early Hai hour.
The pouch belongs to Bai Zhi.
We also learned that Bai Zhi
was found by He Xun ten years ago
and brought
to Mingguang Temple for treatment.
She must be very close to Huiwu.
That night,
did you see Huiwu?
I didn't.
Huiwu claimed that
Bai Zhi left during the early Xu hour.
He was clearly lying.
The burn
on Sun Mao's hand was deliberate.
It was meant
to cover up
the bite mark he got earlier.
They both
deliberately hid the bite mark.
Both of them
are covering up Sun Mao's death.
Could it be
they're protecting the killer?
Bring Huiwu in for questioning.
Keep it quiet.
And ask the monks
about Huiwu's whereabouts that night.
- Yes, sir.
The journey of life
is like sailing on a vast ocean.
The worldly hardships we face
are all meant
to temper our souls.
Hold on to kindness,
and the Buddha will protect us
through countless difficulties.
Abbot Huiwu.
Commissioner Di requests your presence.
May you comprehend the true teaching
in this impermanent world,
and thereby find
comfort and peace for your soul.
Amitabha.
Let's go.
(Silence, Clear the Way)
Amitabha.
Thank you, sir,
for dismissing the guards
and allowing me
to keep my dignity.
Abbot.
How long have you known Bai Zhi?
Bai Zhi and I
arrived at Mingguang Temple
on the exact same day.
At that time,
she was only ten.
Settle in for today.
Tomorrow, you will be formally ordained.
Yes.
Abbot!
I found a child by the river!
She's badly hurt.
Please save her!
I stayed by her side
until she woke up,
and until she fully recovered.
What exactly
did you see that night?
Sir.
The lay monk, Jia Zhishan,
claims that he saw Abbot Huiwu last night
dragging something heavy
in the Repentance Room.
During the late Xu hour last night,
Bai Zhi claims
she saw Sun Mao in the Repentance Room,
and Sun Mao
tried to assault her.
So Bai Zhi struck him
with the incense burner.
Later,
I searched Sun Mao's residence
and found Bai Zhi's pouch.
(Record of Lian, Record of Lady Gui)
It was locked up
with the case files
of those two dead women.
Sun Mao must have discovered something,
which is why you silenced him.
No!
It was Sun Mao...
He had wicked intentions
towards those women.
He's had his eyes on Bai Zhi
for a long time.
Not only did he snatch her pouch,
but he also...
I treat Bai Zhi
as if she were my own daughter.
That night,
I was reciting sutras in the main hall.
But the rain leaking from the roof
soaked my clothes.
So I got up
to go change.
I knew
Bai Zhi would be there at that hour,
so I passed by the Repentance Room.
I never expected to stumble upon
Sun Mao's shameless act.
Master!
Don't be afraid.
Go back to your home.
Hurry!
Huiwu!
What are you doing?
You...
(Preview of Next Episode)
Tongues ripped out.
Eyes gouged out,
and mouths sewn shut.
To see nothing,
and say nothing.
They must have
said something they shouldn't have.
Somebody!
♪Night covers the long streets♪
♪The city remains silent♪
♪Wind turns the old pages♪
♪Words still left unspoken♪
♪Bloodstains still hold their warmth♪
♪Lamplight slowly tilts aside♪
♪Who hides in the shadows♪
♪Still circling around the truth?♪
♪Love is born from desire♪
♪Hatred rises out of greed♪
♪One thought becomes a snare♪
♪A lifetime trapped within♪
♪Someone once warned me♪
♪To stop upon this shore♪
♪But sunlight burns too fiercely♪
♪Fragile eyes break too easily♪
♪If one thought retreats♪
♪Then all things rest in peace♪
♪But in this world♪
♪Who will make the final judgment?♪
♪If truth is cold as a frosted blade♪
♪Still I walk ahead♪
♪Let it pierce through♪
♪The illusions before my eyes♪
♪Layer upon layer of deception♪
♪Covering every heart♪
♪How many people♪
♪Weave their own cocoon♪
♪Yet call it♪
♪Fate?♪
♪Life and death♪
♪Balanced on a single line♪
♪Light and shadow♪
♪Hanging side by side♪
♪Goodness is not absolute♪
♪Nor is evil ever complete♪
♪In the end, it is only♪
♪A single misguided thought♪
♪If unveiling the truth♪
♪Requires abandoning tenderness♪
♪Then this answer♪
♪Can it still remain true?♪
♪When love and law♪
♪Stand against each other in silence♪
♪Which figure before me♪
♪Am I meant to believe?♪
♪If truth is cold as a frosted blade♪
♪Still I walk ahead♪
♪Not for fame or glory♪
♪Nor caring who wins or loses♪
♪Human nature is clouded♪
♪Yet still reflects the stars♪
♪Though this world♪
♪Is filled with mud and mire♪
♪There is still a light♪
♪Worth pursuing♪
♪Every case has its ending♪
♪But night does not always fade♪
♪The wind stops, the pages close♪
♪Yet hearts remain unsettled♪
♪If justice stands♪
♪Without mercy beside it♪
♪Then how is it♪
♪Any different from a blade?♪
♪If truth is cold as a frosted blade♪
♪Still I walk ahead♪
♪Even if the world♪
♪Refuses to answer♪
♪When every hidden truth♪
♪Finally reveals itself♪
♪I only wish♪
♪To hold on♪
♪Within the darkness♪
♪To the heart♪